你吃了我的薯条吗
Did you eat my fries?
你不该就那么放着
You shouldn't have left them.
那是什么
What is that?
不知道
I have no idea.
快报警
Call 9-1-1!
再坚持下  卡塞尔
Almost there, Castle.
两周就好了
Just another two weeks.
已经两周了
It's already been two weeks.
两周永远到不了头
Two weeks is an eternity.
也许我们下次去滑雪
Yeah, well, maybe next time we go skiing,
你就别卖弄了
you're not gonna be such a show-off.
我没有卖弄
I wasn't showing off.
好吧  我是卖弄了一点点
Okay, I was showing off a little bit.
我跟你发誓
But I swear to you,
我闭着眼就能玩后手抓尾板
I can do a tail grab with my eyes closed
而不会摔断膝盖
and without breaking my kneecap.
我走了
Well, I am off.
静修的地方没有手机信号
Now the retreat is out of cell phone range,
如果你生日当天我没打电话
so if I don't call you on your birthday,
并不是因为我忘记了
it is not because I have forgotten.
我不会认为你是忘记了
I won't think it's because you've forgotten.
我会认为你有其它的安排
I'll think it's because you made other plans.
等等
Now wait a minute.
你和凯瑟琳这周本该去
You and Katherine were supposed to be
博拉博拉岛庆祝的
celebrating in Bora Bora this week.
不  你是对的
No, you're right.
静修开心些
Have a great time on your retreat...
别管你独生儿子的生日了
On your only son's birthday.
这是水疗之旅  亲爱的  可不是内疚之旅
It is a spa trip, darling. Not a guilt trip.
他是你的了
He's all yours.
一周后见
See you in a week.
再见
Bye.
好了  卡塞尔
Oh, come on, Castle.
别自怨自艾了
Stop feeling sorry for yourself.
我会订位子
I'll get us a reservation
你生日时我带你去个好地方
and I'll take you somewhere nice for your birthday.
有博拉博拉岛那么好吗
As nice as bora bora?
凯瑟琳  你的司机来了
Katherine, your ride is here.
太好了
Oh, great.
-司机  -对  发现了尸体
- Ride? - Yeah, we had a body drop.
我叫他们来接我
I asked the boys to pick me up
这样我有时间给你做早餐
so I'd have enough time to make you breakfast.
我又错过了一件案子  不  别这样
I'm missing another case? No. Come on.
伙计们  带上我吧
Guys, take me with you.
不  你好转前不行
No! Not until you get better.
卡塞尔  膝盖怎么样
Castle, how's the knee?
膝盖没什么  我快闷死了
It's not the knee so much as the boredom.
我以为你们作家喜欢独处
I thought you writers liked being alone.
如果我能写的话
Yeah, if I could write.
但是止痛药让我有些糊涂
But the painkillers make me a little loopy.
昨晚我在一句话中
Last night I used the word "Speculate"
用了三次"推测"这个词
three times in the same sentence.
你肯定很无聊
You must be bored.
你都玩起《后窗》了
You've actually gone "Rear window."
阿丽克西斯给我的  想让我开心起来
Alexis got me those as a joke to cheer me up.
我还没有沦落为偷窥狂
I have not yet resorted to voyeurism.
那是你的遗憾了
Then you are missing out.
什么  让我看看  给我
What? Let me see. No, hey--give me.
哥们  她刚准备取下浴巾
Dude, she was just about to take off her towel.
-浴巾取下了  -真的吗
- Oh, the towel is off. - Really?
是的
Yeah.
除非你们看的是具死尸
Unless the body that you're looking at is dead,
我建议你们放下望远镜
I suggest you drop those binoculars.
卡塞尔
Okay, Castle.
我会尽快打电话查看你的情况
I will call you and check on you soon.
我通过电话做顾问怎么样
Hey, what if I consult by phone?
可以假装我是查理  你们是我的霹雳娇娃
We could pretend I'm Charlie, and you're my angels.
为什么男人生病或受伤时
Why are men such babies
就变得这么孩子气
when they get sick or injured?
这跟进化有关
It's an evolutionary thing.
这样男人可以让女人照顾他们
Men who can get women to take care of 'em,
这样生存的机会比较大
Well, they have a greater chance of survival.
不是吧  埃斯波  你在哪里看到的
Really, Espo? Where'd you read that,
"你自己瞎编"杂志吗
"You're making it up" magazine?
蕾妮  什么情况
Hey, Lanie. So what have we got?
抱歉  亲爱的  情况很不好
Sorry, sweetie. It's a bad one.
头部多处挫伤
Multiple contusions to the head,
从头盖骨的破碎情况来看
evidence of fracturing at the base of the skull,
鉴于伤痕  我敢说
from the patterning, I'd say she was
是被那个球棒反复击打造成的
repeatedly struck by that bat.
知道死者身份吗
Do we know who she is?
发现她的保安确认她是克莱拉·德温特
The guard who found her IDed her as Clara Dewinter--
35岁  住在皇后区  已婚
35, lives in queens, and married.
她大半夜的在这个小巷做什么
What was she doing in this alleyway in the middle of the night?
她是国税局税务师
She was an I.R.S. Agent.
在这里上班
Worked in this building here.
显然她是加班了
Apparently, she was working late.
员工有时候穿过这条小巷
The employees sometimes cut across the alley
走到隔壁的停车场
to get to the parking garage next door.
有目击证人吗
Do we have a witness?
没有  但有比目击证人更好的东西
No, but we may have something way better.
这是什么
What the hell is that?
不知道  女士
No idea, ma'am.
从未见过这样的情况
Never seen anything like it.
埃斯波
Espo?
这是红外摄像头
It's an infrared camera.
凶手可以戴着
So our attacker could be wearing
高强度的红外光
some sort of high-intensity I.R. Lights,
肉眼看不到  但能屏蔽摄像
which would be invisible to the eye but blinding to that camera.
对于街头犯罪来说相当高级啊
That's pretty sophisticated for a street criminal.
不  这不是街头犯罪
No, this wasn't a street crime.
凶手知道摄像机在那里  采取了措施
The person knew that that camera was there and took precautions.
这是有计划的谋杀
This was a premeditated murder.
等等  倒回去
Wait. Go back.
就是这里
Right there.
这是凶手的车  好了
That's our killer's car. All right.
让技术人员分析图像查明车型
Let's have tech filter that image for make and model
看能不能看清楚凶手的脸
and let's see if they can get us a better look at our attacker's face.
因为裁员  她的工作量增加了
With all the cutbacks, her workload increased.
她一周会加几次班  赶上进度
She'd stay late a couple of times a week trying to catch up,
她加班时  我就在商店加班
and on those nights, I'd pick up an extra shift at the store.
你最后一次见到她是什么时候
And when was the last time you saw her?
我们大概七点吃的晚餐
We had dinner around 7:00,
然后
Then, uh...
我们就都回去工作了
we both went back to work.
她看起来如何  紧张不安吗
And how did she seem? Was she nervous, upset?
没有  看起来挺好的
No. She was fine.
你妻子在国税局是做什么工作的
And what--what exactly did your wife do for the I.R.S.
她是调查员
Uh, she was an investigator.
调查逃税的人
She went after tax evaders.
那她一定有很多仇人了
So she must have made enemies.
是啊  基本上她审计过的人都是
Yeah, pretty much everyone she audited.
有没有哪个人找过她麻烦
And was there anyone in particular that she had trouble with?
事实上  真有一个
Actually... yeah.
我们几星期前在外面吃饭
We were out at--out at dinner a couple of weeks ago,
就有一个男的冲进来
a-and this guy comes barging into the restaurant
说克莱拉毁了他
accusing Clara of destroying his life.
她有告诉过你他是谁吗
Did she tell you who he was?
就是一个她捉到逃税的人
Just another tax cheat she took down.
她说没什么关系
She said it was no big deal,
但我看得出来  她很紧张
but I could tell, she was rattled.
能跟我描述一下那个人吗
Can you tell me what he looked like?
一米八
6 feet...
黑头发
dark hair.
你该去她单位查查
You should check with her work.
她答应我会去投诉的  所以...
She promised to file a complaint, so...
看来今天晴空很晴朗啊
Looks like we got some beautiful clear skies with us today.
今天是顺风  我们很快就能到达  伙计们
A nice tail wind's gonna get us there right away, folks.
我们会在天黑前到达的
We'll be there zero dark thirty, zero dark quarter to.
很好  红五号  状况不错
Nice, red five. You're looking good.
不  我这儿出了点问题
Oh, no. I've got something wrong.
这可不妙
Ooh, that's not good.
躲避  躲避  躲避
Evade! Evade! Evade!
不
No!
有幸存者吗
Survivors.
大多数国税局调查员都受过威胁
Look, most I.R.S. agents get threats.
这活儿就这样
It's the nature of our business.
德温特太太最近上报过吗
Did Mrs. Dewinter report any recently?
没有
No.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你要明白
You have to understand,
克莱拉这种人很少有
Clara was a rare breed--
她是真心喜欢这份工作
an I.R.S. agent who actually liked her job.
这和她受到威胁有什么关系
What's that have to do with her being threatened?
原因在于
The thing is,
每起投诉都要去调查
each threat requires an investigation,
这会让上面的人很头痛
which is a headache for upstairs.
投诉的调查员的业绩评估会受影响
It's an unwritten rule that agents who report threats
这是不成文的规矩了
don't fare well on performance reviews.
这个不成文的规矩很可能害死了她
Well, that unwritten rule may have gotten her killed.
既然你没有她的投诉记录
And since you don't have a record of the threat,
那我们只好查她一年内的
we're gonna have to take a look at her audit files
审计文件了
going back at least a year.
肯定是作家
Must be writers.
最好是孩子病了急需钱
Oh, that better be for a sick child.
真好啊  年轻
Oh, to be young and...
还没工作
underemployed.
稳住  慢点
Whoa. Hold on, guys. Slow down.
这可不是比赛
Not a race.
或者关上百叶窗啊
Maybe close the blinds.
好吧  好好玩吧
All right, you kids. You have fun.
有人提前回家了
Someone's home early.
有没有搞错
Really?
你这会儿还亲他
You're gonna kiss him now?
也许下次
Oh, maybe next time,
出轨前得三思而后行啊
you'll think twice about being cheatin' cheaters.
有人可要好好解释了
Someone's got some 'splaining to do.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
技术部没办法辨别出
So... tech couldn't get us a better look
袭击者的脸
at the attacker's face,
不过明早之前应该能查明车型
but they're hoping to have an I.D. on the car by morning.
你们查得怎么样了
How's it going in here?
克莱拉的同事想不起来
Well, Clara's colleagues don't remember
她提过被威胁的事
her mentioning any explicit threat.
但是如果想找人生被毁掉的
But if we're looking for people whose lives were ruined,
会有很多嫌疑人
there's no shortage of suspects.
有房产被收回的
We've got houses that were repossessed,
银行存款被扣押的
bank accounts that were seized,
公司倒闭的
businesses that were shut down,
这才看了两个月的
and we're only a couple of months in.
那就列个名单出来
Okay, so let's put a list together
找出他们的照片
and pull photos...
看看她老公能认出来谁
see if the husband recognizes anyone.
好
Right.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
你在哪
Where are you?
在分局  怎么了
I'm at work. Why?
你说会带晚餐回来
You said you were bringing home dinner.
我回去时买啊
Yes, on my way home.
你什么时候出发
So when are you leaving?
快了
Soon.
快了是什么时候
When's soon?
大概  半小时
Like in... half an hour.
好吧
Fine.
闭嘴吧
Shut up.
他绝对发现了
Ooh, he is so on to you.
这就来了
Here it comes--
不可避免的分手
the inevitable, huge breakup.
别别别
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
千万别  别拿刀
Don't, don't. Don't take the knife.
别啊
Don't...
不
No. Uh...
卡塞尔  你催我也没用...
Castle, I'm not gonna get there any faster--
不是  不是  贝克特  听我说
Oh, no, no, no, no, Beckett, Beckett, listen...
我好像目睹了一桩凶案
I think I just saw a murder.
2009.3.9-2013.4.1 4 years 48 months 212 weeks 1484days 100 episodes.
Always be with you!!!
他们怎么不逮捕他啊
Why aren't they arresting him?
我知道我看到了什么
Look, I know what I saw.
他拿了一把刀  跟着她进了卧室
He took a knife and followed her into the bedroom.
我看过卧室了
I looked in the bedroom.
一切正常  我发誓  没有血没有尸体
Everything was fine. No blood, no body, I swear.
你看过床底下吗  衣柜里呢
Did you look under the bed, in the closet?
卡塞尔  那家伙很放松也很配合
Castle, the guy was relaxed and fully cooperative.
没有搜查令都让我进屋查看了
He let us poke around without a warrant.
他很可能把尸体藏起来了
So he probably hid the body.
如果他那么镇定  可能是个精神病
If he was completely calm, he could be a psychopath.
那他女朋友呢
What did he say about the girl?
他承认他们吵了一架
He admitted they had a fight,
分手了  然后她就走了
they broke up, and she left.
不可能  那样我会看到她的
Not possible. I would've seen her.
你是一直都在看着吗
So you were watching the whole time?
我
I...
也不是一直看着  我总得...
Well, not the entire time. I had to--
她可能离开了  但你没看到
So she could've left and you didn't see?
那的确有可能  但是...
It's possible, but--
他给她电话了
Because he called her.
他把电话递给我  我还跟她说话了
Handed me the phone. I spoke to her.
她确认了他所说的  她当时在车里
She confirmed his story. She was in the car
正在去费城她妈妈那里的路上
on her way to her mom's house in Philadelphia.
好了  谢谢  伙计们
All right, thanks, guys.
我没发疯
I'm not crazy.
的确  但你一直拥有生动的想象力
No, but you do have a vivid imagination...
而且你被憋在家两周了
And you've been stuck inside for two weeks.
你看窗对面的那栋楼做什么
What were you doing looking out the window anyway?
-我  -太无聊了吗
- I was... - bored?
你是看到了你想看到的东西
So you saw what you wanted to see.
你上次吃止痛片是什么时候
When did you take your last painkiller?
我没有出现幻觉
I was not hallucinating.
得了吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你现在瘸着腿  拿着望远镜
You're here with a broken leg, binoculars,
看到对面上演《后窗》的现实版剧情
seeing a "Rear window" scenario play out across the way.
这可能性有多大
I mean, what are the odds?
巨大的可能
Astronomical.
好了
All right.
我去做晚餐  然后扶你上床
I'm gonna make us some dinner and then get you to bed.
不是吧你
Seriously?
我可以解释的
I can explain.
不必了
Please don't.
听着  他在公寓里来回踱步
Listen, he was pacing back and forth in his apartment,
他不断看向卧室
and he kept looking towards the bedroom.
然后  他睡在沙发上了
And then he slept on the couch.
你明明有张松软舒适的大床
Now why would you sleep on the couch
为什么要睡在沙发上呢
when you have a perfectly good bed?
我也该问你同样的问题
I could ask you the same question.
我来告诉你原因
I'll tell you why.
因为他在里面藏了一具尸体
Because he had a dead body in there.
莱恩和埃斯波西托没有发现
Ryan and Esposito didn't find it
因为他藏起来了
Because he hid it.
你知道自己在干什么吗
Do you realize what you're doing?
你现在完全痴迷于这件事
You're obsessing over this
因为你没有其他可痴迷的东西
because you have nothing else to obsess about.
你今天不如跟我去警局吧
Why don't you just come with me to the precinct?
把注意力放在真的谋杀案上
Focus on a real murder
而不是把时间都浪费在幻想出的案子上
instead of wasting your time on an imaginary one.
实际上  我打算
Well, actually, I was thinking about just, uh,
今天试着写作
trying to do some writing today.
好吧  希望你说的"写作"不是指
Okay, as long as by "writing," You don't mean
盯着窗户  对邻居眉目传情
staring out the window and ogling at your neighbors.
不会  那样不道德也是在侵扰人家
No. That would be immoral and intrusive.
说得好像你从没干过这种事一样
Yeah, like you've never done that before.
吉米·斯图沃特怎么样了[《后窗》主演]
Hey. How's Jimmy Stewart?
大半夜都睡不着
You know, up half the night
等待着那个邻居转移尸体
waiting for the neighbor to move the body.
技术人员对小巷杀手的车分析得有结果了吗
So did tech get anything on our killer's car in the alley?
是的  他们分析出那是新款
Yeah, they identified it as a late-model,
浅色CLS550车
light-colored cls550.
我已经安排人翻查克莱拉的审计纪录
I've got folks combing over Clara's audit records
看看有没有人把这辆车列为申报物
to see if anyone lists that vehicle on their return.
我刚跟克莱拉公司的保安通完电话
So I just got off the phone with security at Clara's office.
几周前
A few weeks back,
这家伙试图用暴力闯过保安的阻拦
this guy tried to muscle his way past security.
他们试图扣留他  但被他突围了
Now they tried to detain him, but he broke free
然后他冲出了停车场  开的是
and he tore out of the parking lot in...
CLS550的车
A cls550.
这人很像加文说来纠缠他老婆的家伙
This looks like the guy Gavin said was after his wife.
是的  所以我把这张照片
Yeah, so I compared that photo
和克莱拉的审计文件进行对比
to Cara's audit files,
然后我找到了这个人
And I got a hit on this guy--
丹·瑞纳
Dan Renner.
他是个反政府  提倡自由的激进分子
He is an anti-government pro-freedom hothead
依靠在布鲁克林开的连锁干洗店发了横财
who made a fortune on a chain of dry cleaners in Brooklyn
他已经将近10年没交过税了
that he's neglected to pay taxes on in nearly a decade.
因为克莱尔的审计  他正面临刑事起诉
And because of Clara's audit, he's facing criminal charges
他妻子刚刚提出了离婚申请
And his wife just filed for divorce.
听上去他一定恨不得用斧头劈了克莱拉
Sounds like someone who has an ax to grind.
或是挥棒行凶  去把他带过来
Or a bat to swing. Pick him up.
好的
Yeah.
你买了绳子和帆布
You bought rope and a tarp.
你要帆布干什么呢
Now what would you need a tarp for?
那是血
It's blood.
你要洗掉...
You're washing away the--
他要洗掉血...
He's washing away the bl--
他们抢走了我的房子  我的婚姻
They took my house, my marriage,
我很可能要被判入狱
I was facing a jail sentence.
所以  是的
So, yeah,
我想跟德温特太太谈谈
I wanted to have a few words with Mrs. Dewinter
关于自由国土的一些事
about the land of the free.
那并不代表我杀了她
That doesn't mean I killed her.
你知道那是什么吗
You know what that is?
那是辆银色CLS550的车  就跟你开的一样
That's a silver cls550, just like the one you drive,
从她的被害现场逃离
fleeing her murder scene.
是跟我曾经开的那辆一样
Just like the one I drove.
我的550车两周前已经被联邦探员没收了
Look, my 550 was seized by federal agents two weeks ago.
你们可以去查
You can check.
考虑到德温特太太原本打算为我做的事
And given what Mrs. Dewinter was gonna do for me,
我是最不希望她死的人
I'm the last person who wanted her dead.
她原打算为你做一件事
Going to do for you?
是的
Yeah.
她一周前来找我的
She came to see me a week ago,
她说她需要帮助  如果我帮了她
said she needed a favor, and if I helped her,
她可以让我免于遭受刑事起诉
She'd make the criminal charges go away.
她会需要你帮什么忙
What kind of a favor could she possibly have wanted from you?
因为我把钱藏得有多好
Because of how well I hid my money--
假名字  多重身份
Fake names, multiple I.D.s--
她让我帮她消失
She asked me to help her disappear.
消失
Disappear?
是的  她说如果我帮她弄个新的身份
Yeah. She said if I helped her get a new identity,
她就会帮我找回原来的生活
she'd help me get my life back.
为什么她想要个新的身份
And why would she want a new identity?
她没说
She didn't say.
但现在她死了  我就完了
But now she's dead, and I'm screwed.
瑞纳先生  两天前的晚上1点38你在哪
Mr. Renner, where were you 2 nights ago at 1:38 a.M.?
在我妹妹家
At my sister's.
贝克特  卡塞尔的电话
Beckett, Castle's calling.
他说有紧急情况
He says it's an emergency.
这算哪门子的紧急情况
This is not an emergency.
我撞见他的手上沾满鲜血  真正的满手红
I caught him red-handed. Literally red-handed.
那就肯定是血吗
Ooh, so then it's gotta be blood?
还有其它可能吗
What else could it be?
红油漆  番茄汁
Red paint, tomato juice,
甜菜  红丝绒纸杯蛋糕
beets, red velvet cupcakes.
他买了帆布和绳子
He bought a tarp and a rope.
拿进了卧室
He brought them into the bedroom,
我敢打赌
where I'm betting right now,
他正在把她的尸体切成小块
he's cutting her into portable pieces.
去申请搜查令
Get a warrant.
在证据被销毁之前搜查那里
Search that place before there's no evidence left.
埃斯波西托跟她说了话
Esposito spoke to the girl.
我们知道她还活着
We know she's alive.
你们怎么知道她们是同一个人
How do you know it's the same girl?
他可能花了钱请人伪造不在场证明
It's possible he paid someone to be his alibi.
或者有可能整件事都不是这样的
Or it's possible something else entirely is going on here.
听着
Look...
我知道你很寂寞  很想我
I know that you're lonely and that you miss me.
我也想你啊
I miss you, too.
但你不用一直编故事
But you don't have to keep making up things
引我回来
to have me come back here.
等等  你以为这是我引你回来的小花招
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You think this is a ploy to get you here?
听着  我不是有意这么说
Look, I don't mean to be that--
我知道你的意思  好吗
No, I know what you mean. All right?
我也知道自己看见了什么
And I know what I saw.
好吧  跟你说
All right, you know what?
我得回分局了
I have to get back to the precinct.
天呐  你真的不信我
Wow. You really don't believe me.
回头见
I'll be back later.
跟你说  算了吧
You know what? Don't worry about it.
我没事
I'm fine.
紧急情况是什么
What was the emergency?
他让我去申请搜查令
He wanted me to get a warrant
搜查街对面那间公寓
to search the place across the way.
他好像特别重视这件事
Looks like he's taking this whole thing pretty seriously.
我们有必要担心他吗
Should we be worried?
我只希望他别做什么傻事
I just hope he doesn't do something stupid.
丹·瑞纳这边查得怎么样了
Where--where are we with Dan Renner?
他的不在场证明成立了
His alibi checks out,
关于他的车  说的是实话
and he was telling the truth about his car.
可能关于克莱拉的事也是实话
Maybe he's telling the truth about Clara as well.
深入调查一下她的生活情况
Let's dig deeper into her life,
看看能有什么发现
see if we can find anything.
谢谢
Thanks.
他要处理尸体
He's getting rid of the body.
贝克特这下必须信我了
Beckett's gonna have to believe me now.
很好
Okay.
哪个是...好了  开始
Where's the... there we go. There we--there we go.
别介啊
No. No. No!
如果你觉得他在弃尸
If you thought he was getting rid of the body,
你为什么不联系贝克特
Why didn't you call Beckett?
她觉得这些都是我编出来的
Well, she thinks it's all in my head--
是想象力和止痛药产生的副作用
A by-product of my imagination and pain pills.
就像你那段时间确信
Like that time you were convinced
我的艺术老师是连环杀手
my art teacher was a serial killer.
拜托  他看起来就像
Come on. He looked just like the guy
《全美首要通缉犯》节目里的人
from "America's most wanted."
你有没有想过
Did you ever stop to think that maybe
或许一切都有单纯的解释
there's an innocent explanation for everything?
好吧
All right,
要怎么单纯地解释卷起地毯
what is the innocent explanation for rolling up a rug
并在凌晨三点搬出公寓
and taking it out of your apartment at 3:00 a.M.?
也是
Yeah.
太古怪了
That is pretty weird.
对吧
Right?
而且他早晨四点半才回来
And then he didn't come back until 4:30 this morning.
他去了哪
Where'd he go?
我不知道  不过他起床了
I don't know, but he's up now.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
-嗯  他...  -怎么了
- Uh, I--he, uh... - What?
你看到什么了
What do you see?
他在脱衣服
He's taking off his clothes.
什么  望远镜还我
What? Give me those.
真性感啊
Mm. He's cute.
行了
Ooh. All right.
不  我...
No, I...
不是吧
Seriously?
你不该看的
You shouldn't be watching this.
是啊  你也不该看
Yeah, neither should you.
搞什么...
What the...
好恐怖
That's creepy.
盯着电话看它也不会响的
Staring at the phone won't make it ring.
我初中就明白这点了
I learned that in junior high.
也许我应该去看看他
You know what? Maybe I should go over there.
明天是他的生日
I mean, his birthday is tomorrow--
相信我  他准备好了会打给你的
Trust me. He'll call when he's ready.
你一定不想错过这个消息
And you're not gonna want to miss this.
我们又查了一遍克莱拉的所有记录
We went back through all of Clara's records.
发现她是有所隐瞒
Turns out that she was hiding something.
一个超过五十万的秘密银行账户
Over half a million dollars in a secret bank account.
她用尽一切合法手段隐瞒这个账户
She used every legal trick to hide it.
没有人  甚至她丈夫都不知道
Nobody, not even her husband, knew about it.
她年薪七万五
This girl made 75k a year.
怎么弄到五十万的
How'd she get her hands on half a mil?
起初我们以为她勒索了受审方
Well, at first we thought she was shaking down her auditees,
但我们后来追踪了存款
but then we traced the deposits.
发现全部是汤米 瓦伦迪诺本人的
All from businesses owned or affiliated
或隶属于他的生意所得
to Tommy Valentino.
"大鲨鱼"汤米 瓦伦迪诺
Tommy "The shark" Valentino?
国税局公务员为什么收受犯罪头目的钱
Why is an I.R.S. agent taking payoffs from a crime boss?
我不知道  但想要消失
I don't know, but wanting to disappear
后来又在小巷被袭击
and then getting whacked in an alley--
都开始说得通了
It's all starting to make sense.
已经两个小时了
It's been two hours.
他在里面做什么
What's he doing in there?
销毁证据
Getting rid of evidence--
血迹  DNA痕迹
Blood stains... trace D.N.A.
不久之后  所有证据都没了
Pretty soon, there's gonna be nothing left.
他出来了  出来了
Oh, here he comes. Here he comes.
袋子里装了什么
What's in the bags?
他已经把尸体卷在毯子里运出去了
He took the body out in a rug.
可能是衣服  床上用品
That could be clothing, bedding.
那是她的手提包
That's her purse.
如果他们分手了  她不可能不带走手提包
If they broke up, no way she left without her purse.
她没离开那间公寓
She did not leave that apartment,
起码没有活着离开
at least not alive.
他在销毁她的证件
And now he's obliterating her identity.
我们必须给贝克特打电话
We need to call Beckett.
告诉她什么
And tell her what?
说我们看到一个男人戴着手套和口罩吗
That we saw a man donning gloves and--and a respirator?
他完全有可能只是在清扫洗手间
For all we know, he's cleaning the bathroom.
不行
No.
我得让贝克特相信我没疯
If I'm gonna convince Beckett I'm not crazy,
我要证据
I need proof,
确凿的证据
something solid.
爸  你不能闯进他的公寓
Dad, you can't break in to his apartment.
我们需要的所有证据都在那台碎纸机里
All the evidence we need is in that shredder.
那会让我们知道死者是谁
It'll tell us who the victim is.
我们就能证明她失踪了
We can prove she's missing.
要是他抓到你呢
And what if he catches you?
不会的  有你帮忙就不会
He won't, not if I have your help.
下次他离开  我就溜过去看看
Next time he leaves, I'll slip over there.
你给我放哨  确保他没回来
You keep watch, make sure he's not coming back.
我进去  把碎纸机里的东西都拿出来
I go inside, I get whatever's in that shredder,
再出来
and I get out.
最多两分钟
Two minutes, tops.
撑着拐杖吗
On crutches?
医生的确说我需要多锻炼
The doctor did say I need more exercise.
我去吧  我个头更小  速度更快  也更年轻
What if I go? I'm smaller, faster, and younger.
不不不  你要是被抓
Oh, no, no, no. If you get caught,
就会有非法闯入的案底
you get a b&e on your record,
就永远当不了总统了
and you'll never become president.
爸
Dad...
他要逃脱谋杀罪名了
He's getting away with murder.
你有更好的计划吗
You got a better plan?
这里有对你的多项指控
You got a long list of indictments against you,
瓦伦迪诺先生
Mr. Valentino--
袭击  勒索  一级谋杀
Assault, racketeering, murder one--
但是  都没定罪
And yet, no convictions.
我在这方面比较幸运
I'm lucky that way.
你的运气就快用完了
Yeah, well, your luck's about to run out.
我有证据证明你曾付款给我的被害人
I have evidence connecting you to payments made to my vic--
克莱拉·德温特
Clara Dewinter.
我的委托人无可奉告
My client has no comment.
等等  有人杀了克莱拉
Whoa, whoa, wait. Someone killed Clara?
看来他有话可奉告
Oh, it looks like he does have a comment.
你现在承认认识她了吗
So you're admitting to knowing her?
是啊
Yeah.
可我没杀她
But I didn't kill her.
她是我的税务顾问
She was my tax consultant.
你付给一个国税局人员50万
You paid an I.R.S. agent half a million dollars
担任你的税务顾问
to act as your tax consultant?
没错  谁都别想坑我
You bet your ass. No one's gonna Al Capone me.
好  如果这是合法收入
Okay, if this was a legitimate arrangement,
那克莱拉·德温特为什么要大费周章
then why did Clara Dewinter go to such lengths
把那笔钱藏起来
to keep that money hidden?
她是怕她老公发现那笔钱
She hid the money from her husband.
所以她开始才会接这份工作
That's why she took this job in the first place.
她怕他
She was afraid of him.
她要钱脱身
She needed the money to get away.
汤米的不在场证明没问题
Tommy the shark's alibi holds.
案发时他和几个同伴在自己开的夜总会里
He was with some associates at a nightclub that he owns.
那不代表他没有买凶杀人
Doesn't mean he didn't send one of his boys.
听着  如果是他杀了克莱拉
Look, if he killed Clara,
就不会向我透露信息了
he wouldn't have talked to me.
不是他
No.
死者藏钱  计划消失
Hiding the money, planning to disappear--
肯定有别的隐情
Something else is going on here.
你查到她丈夫的什么信息了
So what do you got on the husband?
不多
Oh, not much.
他是皇后区一家知名超市的经理
He's a manager at a big-name supermarket in Queens,
没有前科  结婚七年
No priors, married seven years.
就在三个月前  他买了份一百万的人寿保险
Oh, and he took a million-dollar life insurance policy out
被保人是他的妻子
on his wife only three months ago.
那真是一点都"不可疑"啊
That's not suspicious.
你觉得是他杀了人嫁祸给瑞纳吗
You think he did it and set Renner up?
在餐厅发生那样的事后
After what happened at the restaurant,
要那样做也很简单
it would've been easy.
他只需要租一辆和瑞纳一样的CLS车
All he'd have to do is rent Renner's same CLS sedan
把脸遮住
and keep his face hidden.
还要确保车被人看见
While making sure the car was seen.
好  把他带来
All right. Pick him up.
安全  完毕
All clear. Over.
爸  别
Dad, no.
只管拿上东西走人  完毕
Just get the stuff and get out of there. Over.
只要一分钟  完毕
It'll only take a minute. Over.
漂白剂和油漆
Bleach and paint.
你想掩盖什么
What are you trying to cover up?
血迹
Bloodstains?
就是这个
This is it!
他就是在这里杀人的
This is where he killed her.
所以莱恩才没看见任何血
This is why Ryan didn't see any blood.
都在这里
It was all in here!
爸  爸  他回来了
Dad. Dad, he's coming back.
快出来
Get out of there.
Get out now!
爸
Dad?
是
Yeah.
他进来了  爸  爸  他进来了
He's coming in. Dad! Dad! He's coming in!
没  我暂时处理好了
No, I have it handled for now,
可我不能把它永远留在那里
but I can't leave it there forever.
不
Oh, no!
No.
我在考虑吉米的船
Well, I was thinking Jimmy's boat.
趁他在工作时
While he's at work.
他不会知道的
He'd never know.
你以为是我干的
You think I did this?
你觉得我可能伤害我妻子吗
You think I could possibly hurt my wife?
我说了  我们很幸福
I told you, we were happy.
她妹妹可不是这么说的
Not according to her sister.
她声称克莱拉很怕你
She claims that Clara was terrified of you.
她妹妹
Her sister?
那女人在我们开始交往时就对我有意见
That woman's had it out for me since we started dating.
那克莱拉为什么还要藏钱
Then why did Clara hide money from you,
为什么还要计划离开
and why was she planning on disappearing?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
你三个月前买了一份巨额人寿险
You took out a sizeable life insurance policy
被保人是你太太
against your wife three months ago.
为什么
Why?
我现在就要见我的律师
I'd like my lawyer. Now.
超市里的人确定
The supermarket confirmed
案发时他在超市里
he was there the night of the murder.
10点来的  凌晨3点离开  不可能是他
Came in at 10:00, left at 3:00. Can't be him.
好吧  再去一次那家商店
All right, get up to that store
和当晚所有值班的人都谈谈
and talk to everyone that was there that night.
调查他的经济情况和电话记录
Tear apart his financials and his phone records.
要是他买凶杀人
If he hired someone...
我们要找到那个人
we gotta find out who.
等等  你做了什么
Wait. You did what?
你竟然帮了他
And you helped him?
我   好吧
I di--ah, okay.
我们做了什么不重要
This is not about what we did.
重要的是他做了什么
This is about what he did.
看看这个
And... check this out.
虽然我不能
Now I wasn't able to...
把信用卡拼起来  但是
reassemble the credit cards, but...
我在包里找到了这个
I found this in the bag.
一张储藏室的发票  怎么了
An invoice from a storage facility. So?
不是一般的储藏室  是24小时营业的
Not just any storage facility. This one's open 24 hours.
看他租下这里的时间
Yeah, look what time he rented the space.
凌晨3点43分
3:43 A.M.
昨天凌晨3点
Last night at 3:00 A.M.,
我看见他拖着地毯离开他的公寓
I watched him pull a rug out of his apartment.
你知道地毯恰好能包裹住什么吗
You know what fits in a rug?
尸体
A body.
他打算先把尸体放在那里
That's where he's storing her
等想好了处理方法再去弄
until he can figure out what to do.
或者那个地毯是他女朋友的
Or the rug belongs to his girlfriend,
让他先暂存在储藏室
who asked him to keep it in storage
等她有空了再来取回去
until she's ready to pick it up.
好吧
All right.
那你对漂白剂和油漆又作何解释
Then explain the bleach, the paint.
而且我无意听到他说
And I overheard him say,
"我不能把它永远放在那里"
"I can't keep it there forever."
老爸  快来看  有人来了
Dad, look. Someone's coming.
就是他
That's him.
他就是那个奸夫
That's the guy she was having an affair with.
他来找她  他想知道她去哪儿了
He's looking for her. He wants to know where she is.
要是你现在去  你就能抓到他
If you leave now, you can catch him.
你可以向他询问她的下落
You can ask him where she is.
卡塞尔
Castle--
听着  要是她真的去她父母那里了
Look, if she's really visiting her mother,
那个和她发生婚外情的人
wouldn't the guy she's having the affair with,
那个导致他们婚姻破裂的人
who broke them up,
应该第一个就知道才对吧
be the first to know?
你好  打扰了
Excuse me. Excuse me.
纽约警局  能和你聊聊吗
NYPD. Do you have a minute?
他叫布伦特·兰斯基
So his name is Brent Lansky.
他和艾米丽一起上课
He and Emily have been taking a class together at pace,
他这几天一直给她发短信
and he's been texting her for the past couple of days,
但一直没收到回复
but so far there's been no response.
她父母那里呢
What about her parents?
莱恩问过了
Ryan tracked them down,
他们也没有她的消息
but they haven't heard from her either.
所以我不是个吃药吃昏脑袋的疯子咯
So I'm not a drug-addled crazy?
听着  我知道这听上去很可疑
Look, I know it sounds suspicious,
可是没有发现尸体  也没有人口失踪报告
but without a body or a missing person's report,
我没有线索继续追查下去
I've got nothing to go on.
你在等着出现线索继续追查的时候
Well, while you're waiting for something to go on,
他早把大部分的证据都销毁了
he's already taken most of the evidence away.
幸运的是  我知道他是怎么
But luckily, I know what he's done with--
谢谢
Thank you.
处理尸体的  就在储藏室
With the body-- in the storage unit.
你是要让我去非法搜查吗
You're talking about an illegal search.
要是你做  那就是非法搜查
When you do it, it's an illegal search.
我做  就只是犯法活动
When I do it, it's just illegal.
卡塞尔  这个主意太烂了
Castle, this is such a bad idea.
不对  是聪明的主意
No, this is a brilliant idea.
我闯进去  找到尸体
I break in, I find the body,
然后我打电话给楼下前台
Then I call downstairs to the front desk,
告诉他们锁被切断了
tell them that the lock has been cut.
当他们来查看情况时
When they come up to see if everything's okay,
他们发现尸体就会报警
they find the body they call the police,
你就有正当的理由了
and you have probable cause.
你只要乖乖站在走廊里
If you stay out here in the hallway,
就不会侵犯任何人的权利
you won't be violating anyone's rights.
就在这里
There it is.
好吧
Okay.
我没想到这点
I did not think this part through.
你只要
If you'd just...
好吧  卡塞尔  但我从没来过这
Fine, Castle. But I was never here.
只要把它展开
Just unroll it.
尸体去哪里了
Where's the body?
在袋子里
It's in the bags.
天啊  是她
Oh, my god. It's her.
卡塞尔
Castle...
是假发
It's a wig.
这里还有很多衣服
And there's clothes in here.
我们能离开了吗   以免被人...
Now can we get outta here before someone...
看到我们
Sees us?
非法搜查  强行闯入
Illegal search, breaking and entering?
我没收回你的警官证算你走运了
You're lucky I don't have your badge.
还有你  你当时脑袋到底在想什么
And you. What in the hell did you think you were doing?
所有的证据  地毯  储藏室
But all the evidence-- the rug, the storage space--
证据
Evidence?
我刚与你怀疑的凶手谈过话  卡塞尔先生
I just spoke to your alleged killer, Mr. Castle.
是他前女友叫他租下那间储藏室的
He got that storage space at his ex-girlfriend's request.
他把她的物品都搬到了那里
He was moving her belongings there,
包括她的地毯
including her rug.
你怎么知道他说的就是事实呢
How do you know he's telling the truth?
没人有她的消息
No one's heard from her.
我们联系到她了  她很好
We contacted her. She's fine.
那油漆和漂白剂又怎么解释
Well, what about the paint and the--and the bleach?
他在家里发现霉菌  想处理一下
He discovered mold and wanted to take care of it.
还有什么
Anything else?
长官  卡塞尔只是
Just-- uh, sir, Castle is just--
给我和警局的脸上抹黑
Embarrassing me and the department?
对了  卡塞尔先生
Oh, and, Mr. Castle,
你的邻居说了  要是你再去打扰他
your neighbor did say that if you bother him in any way,
他就要告你
he will press charges.
然后我会很乐意亲自把你收监
And I will be so happy to take you into custody personally.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
刚刚被骂得屁滚尿流
Is it hard to balance on those crutches
现在是不是拐杖也拿不稳了啊
when you've just had your ass chewed off?
我在车里等你
I'll be in the car.
二位笑星在死者丈夫那边有新发现吗
Did you two comedians find out anything new on the husband?
他的通话记录没什么不正常
Well, there was nothing unusual in his phone
经济状况也没问题
or financial records.
我们找店里所有人谈过
And we talked to everyone at the store.
他们都说他整晚都在
They said he was there all night.
但他们确实提到他行为异常
But they did say that he was acting weird.
怎么异常
Weird how?
他平时上晚班都窝在办公室里
Well, normally on a late shift, he holes up in his office.
但那晚  他整晚都在外面
But that night, he spent all his time on the floor.
他故意让人看见  好有不在场证明
He wanted to be seen 'cause he needed an alibi.
那家伙肯定涉案了
That guy is involved.
你的推测很有理  可问题是
It's a great theory. There's only one problem.
我们没有证据
We have no proof.
会有的
Yet.
我这人不常说这话
Well, I don't say this often,
但这回  对不起啦
But... I'm sorry.
抱歉给你添麻烦了
I'm sorry I got you into trouble,
抱歉我想多了
Sorry I... lost my mind.
卡塞尔  没关系
You know what, Castle? It's okay.
你过于活跃的想象力
Your overactive imagination
确实让许多人伏法
has actually brought a lot of people to justice.
其实  那也正是我喜欢你的地方之一
In fact, it's one of the things that I love about you.
哇
Wow.
除了说"哇"还是说"哇"
And... wow.
祝我生日快乐
Happy birthday to me.
如果这是我的礼物  我等不及要扒开包装了
If that's my present, I can't wait to unwrap it.
待会儿吧  现在我们别再说案子
Later. Right now, let's just forget about the murder,
先吃晚饭  庆祝一下
go to dinner, celebrate your life,
然后回来  再"庆祝"一下哦
come back, and celebrate some more.
听起来太完美了
Sounds perfect.
好了  车还有15分钟才到
Okay, so the car's gonna be here in 15 minutes.
你要从冰箱里拿点喝的吗
Would you like a drink from the fridge?
冰箱
The fridge.
什么
What?
他刚从柜子里拿了一罐汽水
He just got a soda from the cabinet.
所以呢
So?
他怎么会在柜子里拿汽水
So why get it from the cabinet?
怎么不从冰箱里拿呢
Why not get it from the fridge?
怎么不  弄点冰块呢
Why not... get ice?
不
Oh, no.
她在冰箱里
She's in the refrigerator.
衣柜里的塑料盘
Those plastic trays in the closet?
那些不是塑料盘  而是冰箱里的储物架
Those weren't plastic trays. Those were refrigerator shelves.
卡塞尔
Castle...
我不知道盖茨和谁通的电话
I don't know who Gates was talking to on the phone,
但那肯定不是艾米丽
but that was not Emily.
艾米丽就在那冰箱里
Emily is in that fridge.
她不在那公寓里  不在冰箱里
She's not in the apartment. She's not in the fridge.
根本没什么尸体
There is no body!
有  绝对有
Yes, there is.
卡塞尔  你刚还向我道歉呢
Castle, you just apologized to me.
我废除我的道歉  我撤回
I rescind the apology. I take it back.
她就在冰箱里
She's in the fridge.
算了  我们还是下楼吧
You know what? Let's just go downstairs
在楼下等司机
and wait for the driver there.
我哪儿都不去  除非我看清冰箱里是什么
I am not going anywhere until I see what's in that fridge.
什么
What?!
你要一直守在这儿等着他开冰箱吗
You're gonna stay here and wait for him to open it?
如果有这必要的话
If that's what it takes.
好吧
Okay, fine.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
卡塞尔  我为你安排了生日聚会
Castle, I made plans for you,
我打扮得漂漂亮亮
I dressed up for you,
我是不会让你毁了今晚的
and I'm not gonna let you ruin this night.
你想干嘛
So what are you gonna do?
我要到对面去
I am going to go over there
打开那该死的冰箱
and open that bloody fridge,
然后我俩就去吃晚饭
and then you and I are going to dinner
再也不谈这事了
and never talking about this again.
别  别去  太危险了
No, don't do it. It's too dangerous.
你要是毁了我的计划  我再让你见识什么叫危险
Not as dangerous as me if you blow up my plans.
万一他不让你进去怎么办
Well, what if he doesn't let you in?
看看我  他会让我进去的
Look at me. He's gonna let me in.
如果屋里有尸体  他不会让你进的
Not if there's a body in there.
根本没什么尸体
There's not a body in there.
别去  贝克特
No, no, Beckett.
别
No.
不
贝克特  不
Beckett! No!
不
No!
她在哪儿
Where is she?!
她在楼上  她在那公寓里
She's upstairs! She's in the apartment!
等等我
Wait for me!
纽约警局  快开门
NYPD! Open up!
快开门
Open up now!
踹开  踹开  踹开
Kick it! Kick it! Kick it!
贝克特  贝克特
Beckett! Beckett!
贝克特  你在吗  贝克特
Beckett, you there?! Beckett!
贝克特  你在哪儿
Beckett, where are you?
惊喜吧
Surprise!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
Whoo! Happy birthday!
谢谢
Thank you.
都是假的吗
It was all fake?
一切都不是真的
Nothing was real.
你
You...
你让我以为自己疯了
You let me think I was crazy?
你让我以为你要死了
You let me think you were gonna die?
卡塞尔  可我看你之前那么无聊
But, Castle, you-- you were so bored
都无聊两个星期了
over the past couple of weeks,
困在家里  不能查案子
stuck at home with no case to solve.
然后我看到这间房子在招租
And I saw that this apartment was for rent,
我就  我以为
And I just-- I thought that I--
理查德
Richard--
不
No.
这真是
This is...
毫无疑问
without a doubt...
我这辈子最好的生日礼物
the greatest birthday gift of my life!
你怎么办到的
How did you do it?
我找了很多人帮忙
Well, I did have a lot of help.
是啊  好多人帮呢
Yes, you did, indeed.
你们都参与了
You were all in on out?
对啊  迈克尔  布伦特  艾米丽
Mm-hmm. Michael, Brent, Emily--
都是我出色的表演学生
my brilliant acting students.
我嘛  当然了  是大导演
I, of course, was the director.
你俩呢
And the boys?
-没错  -他俩棒极了
- Yeah. - Oh, yeah. They were great.
不过你们根本不用把门踢坏了
Except you didn't have to kick down the door.
-我太入戏了  -我们想逼真一点
- I was in the moment. - We wanted to be convincing.
-对  -阿丽克西斯  你也加入了
- Yeah. - Alexis, you, too?
所以我才给你买望远镜了
It's why I bought you the binoculars.
甚至还有盖茨警监
Even Captain Gates?
是啊  她会抓住一切
Yeah, she jumped at the chance
把你臭骂一顿的机会
to dress you down for any reason.
盖茨警监人呢
Where is Captain Gates?
-她来不了  -真好
- She couldn't make it. - Good.
太好了
All right!
你真是让我大吃一惊
You really blew my mind.
好吧  我觉得最难的一点
Yeah, well, I figured the trickiest part
就是耍你的同时
would be fooling you and...
还得保持严肃的表情
keep a straight face.
行了  恭喜你荣获奥斯卡
Well, you win the Oscar for
最佳假谋杀奖
best pretend murder.
我都不相信这一切都是演出来的
I cannot believe the whole thing was staged.
演出来的
Staged?
怎么了
What?
我觉得我把案子破了
I think I just solved my case.
也就是说你下一步就要跑掉
Does that mean you're gonna have to go run off
去抓坏人了
and arrest someone?
不
No.
现在我还有其他安排
Right now I've got other plans.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
听着  我很抱歉把你找来
Look, I'm sorry I had to drag you down here,
但我觉得你掌握着破案的关键信息
but I think you might actually hold the key to solving this murder.
没问题  但是我把知道的都告诉你了
Sure, but I already told you what I know.
对  你说你在监控录像上发现了谋杀案
Right, that you spotted the murder being committed on surveillance,
然后你就打了911
and then you called 9-1-1.
是的
That's correct.
我看了这录像好几次了
See, I've looked at this video dozens of times,
想看看我能不能找到线索
trying to see if I could find a clue
查出凶手是谁
as to who the murderer was.
然后我就发现我找错了地方
And then I realized, I'm looking in the wrong place.
你看到那里了吗
Do you see that?
看到什么
See what?
要发现它确实有点难
I-it's actually kind of hard to spot.
就是这里的小点
that dot right there.
就是这个不知怎么神奇地
It's graffiti that somehow magically
出现在墙上的涂鸦
appears on that wall.
看好了
Here.
我再给你放一次
I'll play it for you again.
那怎么可能
How is that possible?
我也不知道
I don't know.
唯一的可能的就是
The only way that it's possible
有人修改了画面
is if someone tampered with the feed
用早前录好的影像
and replaced the live image
替换掉了当时的实时录像
with footage that was recorded before that tag was made.
那不可能  除非有人
That would be impossible unless somebody--
有权限进入监控系统
Had access to the surveillance system,
而你刚好有
which you have.
如果这确实是先录好的影像
And if that is indeed a prerecorded image,
那就意味这袭击是假的
then that means that the attack was faked.
而那个先被打死
And that woman that is being beaten
然后扔进垃圾桶的女人
and then thrown into the dumpster
并不是真正的德温特太太
in not the real Mrs. DeWinter.
你发现她从没露出过脸吗
Now do you notice that she never actually shows her face?
就好像是有个和她身材相当人
It's almost as if someone is pretending to be her,
在假扮她一样
someone with the same frame,
那个人和你很像
Someone a lot like you.
那不是我
That is not me.
我猜真正的德温特太太
I'm guessing that real Mrs. DeWinter.
是当晚早些时候在别处遇害的
was killed somewhere else earlier in the evening,
然后凶手把她的尸体放到了垃圾桶里
and that the killer planted her body in the dumpster
好让你和你的同事
so that it would be there
在观看假录像的时候发现她
when you and your colleagues viewed the faked footage.
而那个录像就成了完美的不在场证明
That video is the perfect alibi for the murder.
我都不认识德温特太太
I didn't even know Mrs. DeWinter.
是  但是你认识她的丈夫
No, but you do know her husband.
根据你的人事资料
According to your personnel file,
你几年前在皇后区的一家超市
you worked night security
担任夜间安保
at a supermarket in Queens a year ago.
和德温特先生在一家超市
That is the same store as Mr. DeWinter.
那只是个巧合
That's just a coincidence.
那你一周前租了一辆CLS550也是巧合吗
Is it also a coincidence that you rented a CLS550 a week ago?
我没有杀她
I didn't kill her.
我知道不是你
I know you didn't.
我需要你告诉我是谁
I need you to tell me who did.
他们一年前值夜班的时候认识的
They met a year ago on the late shift
然后就开始了婚外情
and started an affair.
他们一在一起
Once they got together,
加文就意识到他必须摆脱他老婆
Gavin realized that he'd have to get rid of his wife,
他没有选择麻烦的离婚
And instead of a messy divorce,
而是决定杀人灭口
they decided to make a killing.
真是"了不起"的婚姻
Some marriage.
难怪克莱拉想要消失
No wonder Clara wanted to disappear.
是啊  但她还是不够快
Yeah, but she didn't do it fast enough.
那真正的谋杀地点在哪
So where's the actual murder take place?
在德温特家的车库里
In the DeWinters' garage.
吃完晚饭  他就用
After dinner, he bludgeoned her to death
放在过道的棒球棍把她打死了
with the bat that he left in the alleyway,
然后给她换好瑞嘉丝
and then he changed her into the clothes
在录像里穿的衣服
that Rigas wore on that tape.
在他把尸体放在垃圾桶之前
And then just before placing her body in the dumpster,
瑞嘉丝调换了假的录像
Rigas switched to the dummy feed.
完美谋杀
Perfect crime.
是啊
Yeah.
几乎完美
Almost.
我很高兴我能帮你破案
Well, I'm glad I could help with the case,
即便是无心之举
even though it was by accident.
你说自从我们认识后一起破了多少个案子
How many murders do you think we've solved since we met?
我也不清楚  差不多一百个
I don't know. Um... maybe a hundred or so.
一百个
A hundred?
希望还有下一个一百
Here's to a hundred more.
你知道吗
You know...
你
What you...
为我做的
did for me...
还从来没有人为我这样做过
nobody have ever done that for me before.
简直是
That was...
精彩绝伦
epic.
你要知道我现在
You do know that now I will
必须得好好报答你
have to get you back.
是吗  你觉得你能超过我的吗
Really? You think you can top that?
等着瞧吧
Oh just wait and see.